ANCEL LITTO

EU Bluecard holder

Gustava Zemgala Gatve 80, 60-A, Riga, Latvia, LV-1039 +37125713920 | ancel.codes | ancellitto@gmail.com Linkedin | Github

Pragmatic Software Engineer

I have over 8 years of experience in building complex enterprise grade applications. Currently I'm working on a monolithic decomposition of a legacy system to a microservice based architecture. I am a polyglot engineer who believes in using the right technologies for the job and not just sticking to my comfortable technologies. I like to be involved in architecturing solutions by using pragmatic approaches to solve problems. I'm a continuous learner and passionate about coding. I work better in a team and like to share my knowledge, help, mentor colleagues and junior developers.

Technical Skills

- Languages/Technologies: Java 8, Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Docker, Kubernetes, Openshift Angular, Typescript, Ngrx, Rxjs.
- Key Areas of Interest: Java, Spring Boot, Microservice based architecture
- Certifications:
 - -Master Technology Architect Technology Architect(Accenture)
 - -AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
 - -Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer

Core Competencies

- Experience in migrating monolithic application to microservices
- Experience in leading distributed teams
- Implements efficient solutions to complex problems
- Exposure to Agile Methodologies
- Good knowledge in developing algorithms
- Self learner and keeps up to date with the latest technologies

Career History

Accenture, Latvia: (July, 2019-Present)

Lead Software Engineer:(Dec,2020-Present)

Senior Software Engineer: (July,2019-Nov,2020)

Event Management Tool for a large banking institution in Switzerland(July 2020- Present)

Event Management Tool helps to efficiently plan, manage and conduct events organized by the bank for its clients. The tool was built on old technologies and now moving towards newer technology stack using microservices with spring boot, docker, kubernetes and open shift. I am involved in migrating the project to a newer tech stack. I am helping in defining the new target architecture and lay migration strategy to gracefully move away from the legacy technologies.

Technologies: Java 6,8, Spring 5, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift, Angular, Jsf, Weblogic Responsibilities and Roles:

- Lead and guide a distributed team of 5 developers
- . Defining the new architecture for monolithic decomposition to microservices
- . Supporting developers when they are faced with complex issues due to the legacy nature of the application.

Employee Management System(February 2021- Present)

Employee Management System (EMS) is a project targeted to build up the Intern's skills who have newly joined the company. The main focus is to build a system that would help in managing, training and staffing of the interns

Technologies: Java 6,8, JSF, Weblogic, Oracle 10g

Responsibilities and Roles:

- . Responsible for the overall architecture and to provide technical designs like architecture diagrams, solution diagrams, ER diagrams.
- . Responsible for creating requirements and designing solution architecture and provide clarity to all the questions that the Team Lead and Interns have regarding the solutions

Advisory tool for Relationship Managers for a large banking institution in Switzerland(July 2019- July 2020)

The Advisory tool is used by Relationship Managers to engage with their clients. It aggregates data from various downstream services and provides all the necessary information and statistics to the Relationship Manager. I worked as a full-stack developer and used Angular for frontend and Java for backend. Did architecture and groundworks for transforming the monolithic application to micro frontend and microservices. Setup the main

pillars of microservices architecture like service gateway, registry all the way from development environment to production

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Netflix Eureka, Zuul, Ribbon, Micro-services, Micro-frontends, Angular 8, Ngrx, Rxjs, Apache Camel.

Responsibilities and Roles:

- . Design and develop new features
- . Helped in new architecture and migrate to micro front/micro services

Palnar Transmedia Pvt. Ltd : (May, 2017-June 2019)

Senior Software Engineer

Project: Vxplorer (May 2017 – June 2019)

Vxplorer is a Enterprise Content Management framework to cater the needs for managing the content for a company in the food industry in Germany. A core framework was designed and developed from scratch which was used to create multiple solutions for various products across the company. Vaadin and java were the base technologies for developing the frameworks.

Technologies : Vaadin, GWT, Java

Responsibilities and Roles:

- · Solution designing, development and testing of various components
- Gathering requirements from client and clarifying the details
- . Mentoring and assisting the colleagues for solving various technical problems

Project: Movado Portal (March 2018 – June 2019)

An online portal for Movado Group for its employees and user base. I was involved in the development and architecturing of the backend for various stages of the portal. Spring boot is the core technology used as the backend which exposes various services which are consumed by the front end.

Technologies: Spring Boot ,Java,Restful web services

Responsibilities and Roles:

- . Discussing and debating about various solutions and ultimately figuring out the best possible solution
- . Development and architecture of the various services and api gateway

SunTec Business Solution: (July, 2013-May 2017)

Software Engineer

Developed Automated Application Code Generation and Rendering Framework*:

This framework was capable of automatically generating a deployable web application, it could be configured either to generate the entire code base and create a WAR (web Archive) or render the application and deploy it in its own server. I was Responsible for the entire Application Code Generation and Rendering Framework. Developed a web based graphical modeling framework *:

This served as an underlying framework which was used to build various graphical modeling softwares and tools. Developed A viewport from ground up which had the capabilities for zooming and panning an area, it supported Layers and had a custom bufferer which loads only a part of the entire canvas during a point of time which reduced performance overheads.

Developed a web based UML Diagramming Tool*:

This Tool helped in creating class, component, sequence and context diagrams. This was capable of Round trip engineering i.e. generating class diagram for code and generate code from class diagram. The tool was context aware so that it could provided a navigation from component to class to sequence navigation of a specific module. The tool was intelligent enough to provide a dynamic layout for class, component and sequence diagrams

Academic Qualification

Qualification: Bachelor of Engineering-Computer Science

Years: 2009-2013

University: Anna University, India

Qualification: AISSCE Years: 2008-2009 Board: CBSE

Qualification: AISSE Years: 2006-2007 Board: CBSE